Muhammad Noman Riaz

S/o Muhammad Riaz

House No 05, Sheet No 28, Model Colony Malir Karachi, Pakistan Cell: +92 332 2359425

nouman_riaz31@yahoo.com

Dear Sir,

I was excited to find your advertisement. I couldn't wait to submit my resume, which is

enclosed for your review.

I believe that my education, skill set and experience make me a suitable candidate for the vacancy I am highly organized and self-driven individual, passionate about developing my career in the field of HR/Admin & Accounts. Possessing about 8 years of experience of working in HR/Admin & Accounts department, I have gained an extensive insight in this field. My key responsibilities include; Recruitment and selection, Manage schedules, Monitor inventory of office supplies, Performance management, Career planning, Payroll and Benefits & Employee

performance improvement plans.

In my current position with ASE Constructors (Pvt.) Ltd. where I work in the capacity of Assistant Manager HR & Admin, I worked under supervision of qualified senior and responsible

for the above mentioned matters.

Furthermore, I have excellent communication skills and 'can do' attitude. It would be a pleasure to utilize my experience and knowledge for your organization. I am geographically mobile and willing to relocate and travel for business purposes. I anticipate that my job application will take

good credits from your hands.

Thank you for your time and consideration and looking forward to hear from you soon.

Sincerely,

M. Noman Riaz



Muhammad Noman Riaz

S/o Muhammad Riaz Assistant Manager HR & Admin

Contact Details

House No 05, Sheet No 28, Model Colony (Malir) Karachi Pakistan.

+92 332 2359425

nouman riaz31@yahoo.com

Career

Highly recognized in the community, I can meet the challenges that your company will entrust me. I am a recognized expert in the field of HR.

Software

Windows 7, 8, MS Office, OracleERP R12. Adobe Photoshop 7, Adobe PS CS6

Information

Name: M. Noman RiazS/O

M. Riaz®

DOB: 20.09.1992

CNIC: 42000-0808750-3 **Domicile:** Karachi (Sindh U)

Gender: Male **Religion:** Islam

Material Status: Married

Hobbies

Internet Surfing, Watching Movies, Reciting Quran, PC Gaming, Reading Islamic & history books

Professional Experience

Assistant Manager HR & Admin:

Aug 2021 to Present

ASE Constructors (Pvt.) Ltd.

- Managed leaves record of all sites & head office employees.
- Prepare presentation materials, assist with developing communication materials and provide support for HR initiatives.
- Maintain and update employee's personal file over 800 employees.
- Assist in payroll preparation by providing relevant data (absences, bonus, leaves)
- Recruits, interviews, and facilitates the hiring of qualified job applicants for open positions and collaborates with departmental managers to understand skills and competencies required for openings.
- Source applicants through various methods including advertising, job sites and open houses.
- Manage employees' grievances.
- Maintaining HR records, such as those related to compensation, health and medical insurance.
- Prepared appointment letters, warning letters, termination letters, increment letters and mail drafting.
- Managing office supplies stock and placing orders.
- Arrange travel, accommodations & book meeting rooms as required.

HR & Admin Executive:

Feb 2019 to July 2021

Whitepeak Travel & Tourism

- Developed HR policies & ensured employees understand and comply with them.
- Managed employees' grievances.
- Managed human resource staff by recruiting, selecting, orienting, and training employees.
- Managed leaves record and employees personal file.
- Interview applicants about their experience, education and skills & assisting with completing background investigations.
- Book meeting rooms as required.
- Organize a filing system for important and confidential company documents.

HR Executive:

March 2015 to Oct 2018

Shaheen Air International.

- Work closely with the Senior Manager HR to ensure smooth operation of all HR matters.
- Full recruitment process, processing requisitions, screening resumes, conducting phone screens and in-person interviews, and preparing job offers.

- Source applicants through various methods including advertising, job sites, open houses, and career fairs
- Maintain confidentiality of all company and personnel related information.
- Conduct employees training as per aviation requirement; i.e. Aviation Grooming, Safety Procedures, Human Factor & Organizational Procedures.
- Get approval from chairman & director for captains, cabin crew & engineers trainings in abroad.
- Managed employees' grievances, prepare engineers, captain and cabin crew travel, slip & flying allowances.
- Prepared appointment letters, warning letters, termination letters, increment letters and mail drafting.
- Maintained & prepared various HR reports and formats.
- Update employee's leaves record and prepared monthly attendance sheet.

HR & Admin Assistant: Feb 2013 to Jun 2014

PAF KIET.

- Directory maintenance, logistics, equipment inventory and storage.
- Coordinating with departments and operating units in resolving day-to-day administrative problem
- Managing Files.
- Prepare and distribute payroll for staff.
- Coordinating with students to providing free labs and classes for their Projects
- Ensure timely supplies of academic materials to faculty members.
- Maintaining the data of the all visiting faculty.
- Follow university policies, guidelines, laws and regulations.
- Coordination with student Affairs department in preparing and scheduling events
- Keeping student records, academic advising, and statistical analysis.
- Perform HR Functions.

Education:

•	Bachelor of Commerce	2012-2014
	DadaBhoy Institute of higher Edu., 60%, Karachi, Pakistan	
•	Intermediate (Commerce)	2009-2011
	Army Public College, 55%, Karachi, Pakistan	
•	Associate Engineering (Electrical)	2008-2011
	Mono Tech. Institute, 68%, Karachi, Pakistan	
•	Matriculation (Science)	2006-2008
	Sindh Board, 70%, Karachi, Pakistan	

Certification / Courses:

 Aviation Grooming and Orientation CAA Silver Wings, Karachi, Pakistan.

• English Language

Delhi English Language Centre, Karachi, Pakistan

Skills:

MS Office, Adobe Photoshop, Team Work, Communications Skills, HR Tasks, Cash Handling, Working & Coping Under pressure.

Reference:

Will be furnish upon request